<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../xsl/200808.xsl" ?>
<b>
  <e>博彦培训月刊</e>
  <l>第三期</l>
  <e2> 2008.08.10</e2>
  <m>
    <title>The best moment you are experiencing now…</title>
    <author>
    	<name>Ida</name>
    	<intro>博彦培训编辑部主任, 首席记者. 负责编辑部各个环节的组织和综合工作, 包括联络工作, 对采访对象进行采编工作等, 特写 (Feature) 责编. </intro>
    	<email>zhanghongbo@beyondsoft.com / v-honzha@microsoft.com</email>
		<other>MSN: idazhang@live.cn </other>
		<img>ida.jpg</img>
    </author>
    <article>
    	<i> 
    		<section>I have worked for more than half a year now but I still remember the day I took the interview in BYS, felt so nervous and worried waiting for the final result…I think most of us have the same feelings when we took the first interview of our life. 
</section>
    	</i>
    	    	<i> 
    		<section>In July, we have totally 37 new guys joined our team, most of them from the campus hire. They took their first interview when the first day they arrived. Some of them passed but some failed…some of them have the optimistic attitude toward the future but some felt really sad. I have the same feeling with them at that moment because in my eyes their curiosities of the new place just like the children’s nature and all of them have their own expectations. After familiar with each other we began to talk about the daily issues and the status. I know I couldn’t help them a lot to deal with the technical problems or answer the questions they were asked in the interview but every time when you look directly in their eyes you could see the soul inside: How puzzled and helpless they were! However how eager they want to find their own seats in this new place! It’s a challenge but also chance for everyone. In this ever-changing industry we need to find out a way to suit it and keeping us always be needed, that’s the key point. 
 
</section>
    	</i>
    	<i> 
    		<section>Like in a basic kingdom: one king, one chancellor, one general and several civilians. First of all we need to realize the role we are then we should work hard for the wishes finally we could go up step by step. Never try to find the shortcut just be yourself, because you are not students anymore that the teacher always be patient to teach you, once you are working you need to find out the answer by yourself. That’s the life! However we have the team so we could feel much better more than single. Please bring up the team spirit it’s quite important for us. Actually for me I usually feel very happy with my work as every time I always the first person who could see the best part of each new comers once they joined BYS. My friends once told me that sharing makes your life enriched. That’s right. I also believe that communication makes everything easy so please learn how to share and how to communicate with others. Be a good listener first then provide your own opinion. You will really enjoy the whole process, just happy work and happy life.</section>
    	</i>

    	<i> 
    		<section>I am experiencing my best moment in my life…</section>
    	</i>
    	<i> 
    		<section>Believe that the aim of life is to have a nice time, go to nice place and meet nice people. Just enjoy it…J</section>
    	</i>
 
    </article> 
    <topic>
    	<id>2</id>
    	<name>特写(Feature)</name>
    </topic>
  </m>
</b>

