<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../xsl/200807.xsl" ?>
<b>
  <e>博彦培训月刊</e>
  <l>第二期</l>
  <e2> 2008.07.10</e2>
  <m>
    <title>Develop your Career Path</title>
    <author>
    	<name>Grace Gu</name>
    	<intro>Grace Gu.</intro>
    	<email>X@microsoft.com</email>
		<other>MSN: X@live.com</other>
		<img>gracegu.gif</img>
    </author>
    <article>
 		<i>
 			<section>Developing your career requires you to view your development as a path or a direction, rather than a point or a job. Your career is not a one-time decision. It is an interactive process that you refine and redefine as you grow professionally, it is a continuous process that you pursue your passion, your talent and your interests, and it is also a process you well align with the chances/environment you have an reach a best win-win. </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>Here are some basic rules I like, from my experience and good for me, for your information. </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>1.	Focus on yourself, not what others are doing.</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>2.	5 good questions to review and forecast next step at your different career path milestone: What I will be passionate in, What I want to be now and in future, What is my current skill set, The gaps to what I want to be, How to reduce those gaps via chances available?</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>3.	Always try your best, it is best and fastest way you get improved, it will help you improve yourself and gain more chances,  though sometimes it takes time for you to see the result. </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>4.	 Do it, not stuck there thinking, experience will give you wisdom to make obstacle clear.</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>5.	CQ+PQ&gt;IQ   (CQ means curiosity quotient 好奇商，PQ means passionate quotient 激情商)-from the book-the world is flat, one of the best I have read.  CQ and PQ will help you better self learning and self encouraging, continuously do well.</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>6.	Be open,  be modest, and be friendly to other, no one will learn fast , will learn more than one with an open heart to absorb anything better than what he/she has, one without a good character is difficult to succeed, it is a win-win world.  Win-win can be understood as 互相帮助，one old Chinese saying 吃亏是福 can be positively explained here as  Give then Take, helping others and others will help you. </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>7.	Read more and ask more, go to expertise when you feel confusion, Books can always be one of the best expertise.  I usually found out that some tips have been in books for long time before I summarized them based on my suffering and success.  </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>Career and professional development in our BU is also an ongoing process of aligning your individual development plans with our BU business plans, to achieve an optimal match between your professional growth and BU business objectives.</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>BU Values</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>Those values are more useful than you thinkJ</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>1.	Be Independent and good ownership. Ownership means you are expected to be owner of your tasks, independently and proactively think ways to get things done, take ownership if that fails. </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>2.	Initiative. You are expected to be initiative in daily work, no one will tell you the detailed steps and ask you frequently what support you need, you are the one to drive everything and get it done 
</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>3.	Creative. Believe you are the most experienced in the area you own, bravely and creatively to raise any new ideas or any questions, you will lose anything but gaining new knowledge.
</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>4.	Those are also expected, be Passionate and Confident,  Accountable, Pursuing Excellence,  Integrity and honesty.</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>How to think the development here-update and develop your skill set</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>Professional development can be reflected as moving up the career ladder, or changing your position while not just those. Growing and increasing your capability, responsibility and satisfaction within your current role and professional path is also one important part. </section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>The key of your career path grow in our BU is that you will have all kind of opportunities to  update and develop your skill set to top level in the industry.</section>
 		</i>
 		<i>
 			<section>We instruct you to work with you manager to choose some skill sets as your next development goal,  refer to those listed in our performance review, or those detailed in Tester Body of Knowledge.</section>
 		</i>
 
 
 		<gif>
 			<section>management/200807a.gif</section>
 		</gif>
 
     </article> 
    <topic>
    	<id>7</id>
    	<name>管理(Management)</name>
    </topic>
  </m>
</b>

